InterAct Accessories welcomes you to the mind
blowing world of video game enhancements with
our new GameShark Pro. The GameShark Pro, which
is more technologically advanced than any
other game enhancer on the market today, promises
to take your gameplay to higher levels. It's
jump packed with great new features. Let's
take a look.
The GameShark Pro is loaded with hundreds of
codes for more than 100 Nintendo 64 titles,
so you're sure that all the biggest and best
games are included. GameShark Pro contains
enough memory to hold hundreds more GameShark
codes, and the one new feature that makes the
GameShark Pro the ultimate video game enhancer
is its built-in Code Generator. Code Generator
gives you the power to produce your own jaw-dropping,
game-winning GameShark codes, so why wait
for cool new codes when you can produce them yourself?
In this video, you'll discover how the
GameShark Pro will revolutionize your gameplay,
arming you with the power to load the most devastating
codes available, and even showing you how to
take things a stage further and create your
own havoc-wreaking codes of destruction.
The GameShark Pro is preloaded with a huge range
of powerful GameShark codes, and using them
couldn't be easier. From the hundreds of Nintendo 64
titles available on the GameShark Pro, select
the game you've loaded from the game selection
menu, then choose the codes you want to tailor
the game to how you want to play it.
Sometimes certain games won't work with the
GameShark Pro until a special key code is activated.
Now, here's a list of Nintendo 64 games that
require the use of a key code in order to work
with your GameShark Pro. GameShark Pro comes
preloaded with key codes for all of these games,
and these key codes must be activated before
the use of the GameShark Pro with one of these titles.
However, since these games will not work with
the GameShark Pro until the key code has been
activated, you must first insert another game
cartridge into the GameShark Pro in order to
access the menu screen and activate the key code.
To do this, simply choose a game that you know
does not require a key code to work with the GameShark Pro.
This will be your setup cartridge. Now we shall use GoldenEye.
Since you want to play Zelda 64, go to the Key
Codes menu and select the Zelda 64 key code by
pushing the analog stick up or down to highlight
the desired code and pressing the A button to
select it. Because we have the Zelda 64 cartridge,
we can select "Yes" at the warning screen and press
the A button. Once the key code is activated,
turn off your Nintendo 64 system. Remove the
GoldenEye setup cartridge and insert the game
that required the key code. Then turn the system on again.
The GameShark Pro's main menu will appear and
you can select your codes or start the game.
If you don't have the key code game available,
do not select "Yes" at the warning screen. If you
do select "Yes", then the next time you use the GameShark
Pro, the game that you've activated the key
code for must be inserted. Be warned, the GameShark
Pro will not function until the game is inserted into it.
As new games are released, some of them may require
new key codes. Be sure to check out the GameShark
website to find out more information about them.
You can also read more about key codes in the
Using Key Codes section of the GameShark Pro instruction manual.
GameShark Pro's Memory Card Manager allows
you to view the contents of any Nintendo 64 memory
card up to 123 pages in size. Follow the simple
on-screen instructions to load, save, and copy
game save between your memory cards. In addition,
the memory card manager makes it possible to
copy game saves from the EEPROM of your game
cartridges onto standard memory cards. You
can even trade these saves with friends using
InterAct's N64 DexDrive.
The GameShark Pro has a built-in image viewer
that allows you to see graphics stored in the
system memory the last time the freeze button
of your GameShark Pro was pressed so you can
view graphics that would not normally be viewed
during a game.
Every keen game player is aware of the increasing
levels of sophistication arriving with each
new game that hits the shelves. Games are becoming
increasingly more challenging not only to
novice players, but to hardcore gamers too.
And no matter how we grade ourselves in terms
of game playing dominance, sometimes we need help.
And to meet this need, many game publishers
now embed special effects into their games
that allow you to bend the rules. How can we find
special moves, level skips, and so on, which
are unleashed with the use of codes or fancy controller moves?
GameShark Pro redefines the rules, letting you
set the agenda.
Power up with the Turbo RAM and add an extra 4
megabytes of RAM to the Nintendo 64. The Turbo
RAM allows gamers to enjoy the high resolution
graphics and faster gameplay programmed into
compatible and 64 games. Plus, Turbo RAM is
the only third party RAM pack licensed by Nintendo.
Turbo RAM for Nintendo 64 will be available
in quarter two '99.
Now get ready, because we're going to teach
you how to play and hack games like a pro using
the GameShark Pro. Please understand that hacking
your own GameShark codes may be a little difficult at first.
After you study this video and actually try
to find codes on your own a few times, you'll
start to grasp some concepts of video game coding
and the hexadecimal system used when hacking
with the GameShark codes. How does the GameShark
Pro tilt the odds in your favor? Well, it starts
with the codes. A GameShark code is a special
routine that affects the way a game actually works.
You can select any number of powerful codes
to arm you with the ability to blast your games wide open.
This means you can play a game with infinite
life or health, infinite ammo, extra vehicles,
extra weapons, and so on. Whether you want to
simply load in codes to enable you to complete
a particular level, then disable them and go
it alone, or if you want to really cheat by playing
an entire game using the codes, the choice is yours.
Before we look at how GameShark codes work, you'll
first need to understand a little of how the
actual engine of the game functions. Every
game, whether it be a fighting, racing, adventure,
or shoot 'em up title, has a built-in table of events
that holds the information about gameplay variables.
This area might contain values for the current
level, energy, status, number of lives, and so on.
During gameplay, if, for instance, a life is
lost, then the value at a particular memory
location is reduced to reflect the new lower life value.
Likewise, if the game player moves on to the next
level, then the different value within memory
will be increased accordingly. From this you
can see that you can actually affect the way
a game's engine works. You have the ability to
control these values by preventing the game
engine from changing them in the normal way.
GameShark Pro has the ability to prevent the
values in memory from being modified by the
game and it actually takes control of these
locations by forcing alternative values into them.
This is done by the use of GameShark codes. A GameShark
code is made up of two parts. The first part is quite
simply the address of the memory location that
we wish to take control of. This might be the
location that controls lives, for instance.
The second part of the code is the alternative
value that we wish to place there. For instance,
if this location normally contains only two
lives, then the GameShark code for extra lives
might read like this, where the 9 equals 9 lives.
If you simply can't wait for codes for the newest
blockbuster game, then GameShark Pro's built-in
Code Finder is just for you. GameShark Pro
has a powerful Code Generator system which
allows you to find and create your own GameShark codes.
Operation of this feature is quite simple and
you can soon be producing GameShark codes equal
to those already available. One important
point here is that to use the Code Generator
feature, your Nintendo 64 must be fitted with
a 4-meg RAM expander. Once your console is
equipped with the RAM expander, you're ready
to start using the Code Generator. The easiest
way to demonstrate this feature is by example.
From GameShark Pro, start the game as you would
normally without any codes enabled. Look for
any elements you would like to change, for example
number of bullets, lives or money. So in this
case we want to make Duke's pistol bullets unlimited.
To go about finding this code, press GameShark's
freeze button which takes you into the In game
menu. Select Code Generator option. From within
this menu screen, select Known Value Search.
From the next menu, select Equal To. Here we
will enter the value 48 as this represents the
number of bullets Duke has. GameShark tells
us there are over 10,000 possibilities, so
we go back into the game. We need to change our
number of bullets. So to do this we fire once.
OK, so we now have 47 bullets. Press the freeze
button again. The Known Value Search menu will appear.
Select Equal To and enter the new value 47.
Now we have only two possibilities, so we select
View Search Results. The codes we have found
are displayed on the left of the screen. To discover
which of these codes controls Duke's bullets,
we need to try them out. So we select one of the
codes, then return to the game and fire some bullets.
The code that doesn't allow our number of bullets
to be reduced is the correct code. So now throughout
this level, Duke's pistol bullets will remain at 47.
Now we found our code, we need to save it. To do
this, switch your Nintendo console off, then on again.
This takes you back into the GameShark Pro main menu.
Here we're going to Select Cheat Codes. Select
New Game, then Edit Name. Enter the name of the game,
then select it from the game listing.
Select New Code,
enter a name for the code, then edit the code.
The code you have found appears at the bottom
right hand corner of the screen. Press C-right
to highlight the code, then press A to select it.
Your code will now appear in the edit box. Select
Exit and Save, and your code is now permanently
stored in your GameShark.
In some cases, you may not know the value you're
looking for. For example, an energy bar shows no number.
To demonstrate how you would go about finding
an unknown value of this type, we will use Midway's
Mortal Combat Trilogy, where we'll look for
player one's health. From within the Code Generator
menu, select Unknown Value Search, select Start.
This initiates GameShark search and here we
return to the game and lose some of player one's health.
Once we've done this, we press the freeze button
and select Less Than Last.
There are over 1,000,000 possibilities, so
we need to reduce this number to ideally around
20 possibilities, so we return to the game and
lose some more health.
Repeat the process as many times as necessary
to obtain a manageable number of possibilities.
In finding this code, we repeated this process
8 times until we had reduced the number of possibilities
down to 26. Then, by process of elimination,
we deduce which is the code that affects player
one's health. Notice how player one's health
bar doesn't go down.
Then you simply save your newly found code in
the way shown previously.
So now you've seen how you can find and create
your own simple codes. Using the same methods,
you can go on to discover extra characters,
lives, and even create new game scenarios.
Last year we unveiled what many deemed the peripheral
of the show, the DexDrive. The concept behind the DexDrive
is a simple yet brilliant one. Gamers can transfer
Nintendo 64 or PlayStation game saves to their
PC's hard drive where they can be safely stored
and backed up. The unique patented DexPlorer
software program allows gamers to easily manage
their game saves with retrieve, copy, and other
editing functions. When combined with the
Internet, that's where the DexDrive really begins
to shine. With game saves now on PC, they can
be uploaded to and downloaded from the Internet
and e-mailed to other DexDrive users. InterAct
supports the DexDrive with a website that
provides gamers with a plethora of game saves
to download, the opportunity to post their
own game saves, as well as the DexCussion board,
a place to discuss video game topics, and request
specific game saves. DexDrive for Nintendo
64 and the PlayStation are available now.
If you fancy yourself as a real game guru and
GameShark Pro can be connected to a PC, simply
by using a standard printer lead connected
to the parallel port of any PC. Printer leads
are available from wherever you buy your computer accessories.
Simply connect one end to the printer port of
your PC and the other end to the comms port of your
GameShark Pro. Then simply download the special
SharkLink software from the GameShark website
www.gameshark.com. You now have the power to
generate codes using your PC.
We offer several valid sources of the newest
and oldest codes. We have a weekly updated 900
line, 1-900-773-SHARK. There's a free access
website www.gameshark.com and we publish
a bimonthly newsletter called Dangerous Waters.
We also supply codes for your favorite video
game magazines like Game Informer, EGM,
Expert Gamer, and Tips & Tricks. Finally, Prima
Publishing has released two official GameShark
code books that sell in bookstores and game
retailers nationwide.