GameShark is the ultimate game enhancer for the PC.
Now you can rewrite the rules. GameShark takes
the latest and greatest brain-busting games
and blows them apart. If you've experienced
the humiliation of crashing out at level four
of your favorite action-adventure game, then
GameShark is the only tool you'll ever need
to even the odds. With GameShark, you set the agenda.
Now you can choose how to play the roughest and
toughest games. With GameShark, you're in command.
The GameShark doesn't just help you to complete
your games more easily; a unique library of
game enhancements can actually add hours of
game play to your favorite games.
So how does GameShark work? The GameShark contains
hundreds of enhancement codes for the best PC games.
Enhancement codes are special routines which
change the way in which the games work. This
means you can have unlimited energy, extra
lives, invincibility, or indeed any number of
special effects. GameShark’s user-friendly
Interface makes using this advanced cheat
system so simple. Select the game that you're
playing from the cheat selection menu. Each
game has a choice of special cheats developed
to add extra energy, lives, ammo, power, and
much, much more. Then select start and unleash
the power of GameShark.
So what about codes for new games? Although
your GameShark contains hundreds of powerful
cheats for many of the latest games, you will
want to get your hands on new codes for new games
as they come along. As soon as new games are released,
our code cracking team start work to produce
new and interesting cheats for each game.
Clued-up Sharkers simply hit our website at gameshark.com
where they can download the latest codes, sometimes
within hours of the game's release. So there
you have it, you now have all the insider knowledge
you need to blow games apart. Enjoy.